Adrian Göransson

github.com/adriangoransson linkedin.com/in/adriangoransson

+46 709 22 67 19 adrian@adriang.se

About me

Passionate and experienced fullstack developer who is comfortable with most of the common tech stacks in use today. I am professional about my work, but also a light-hearted person who enjoys being social and having fun with my colleagues.



Education

Faculty of Engineering, Lund University

Sep. 2017 - est. Jan 2022

Master of Science in Computer Science and Engineering at LTH. Relevant courses: concurrent programming, algorithms and data structures, compilers, computer communication, data security, functional programming and operating systems.

NTI-Gymnasiet Lund Network technician. Cisco CCNA certified.

2010 - 2013

Experience

Axis Communications — Master Thesis student

Sep. 2021 - est. Jan 2022

Evaluating the OLAP database ClickHouse for real-time analysis of big data and comparing its feature set and performance against ElasticSearch and Pandas/numpy.

Axis Communications — *Software developer*

Oct. 2020 - Aug 2021

Part-time job (Student worker) developing the tools used at Axis for in-device diagnostics. My job has been to optimize collection and inspection of crash dumps.

Lund University — Teaching assistant

Sep. 2020 - Oct. 2020

Teaching assistant for a course in concurrent programming (EDAP10) at LTH. This course was one of my favorites as a student and helping others get through it and understand the concepts introduced by the course was both challenging and fun.

Bitiq — Co-founder, developer

Feb. 2018 - Mar. 2019

Ticket sales platform for student hosted events in Lund. We built a serverless REST api in Go and used Postgres as a database. Web apps developed with Vue were used for purchases, event administration and ticket verification using QR scanning.

Qlik — *Software developer*

Jun. 2018 - Jul. 2018

Summer position where I helped create a proof of concept of a data visualisation tool to further enhance Qlik's data analytics service. Built with Vue and Qlik's chart library Picasso.js.

Beepsend, today Twilio Sweden, is a messaging company specialising in SMS. I was part of a small team building our internal and costumer facing REST APIs with PHP and web apps using Coffee-Script/Javascript (with Chaplin.js). Due to my networking background I was also in charge of managing connectivity over VPN and SS7/Sigtran. I helped set up CI pipelines using Jenkins and Docker.

Skills

Experienced

Languages Javascript (Vue, React), Go, Python, Java, PHP, Rust, HTML, CSS, SQL, Posix shell.

Databases PostgresSQL, MySQL, SQLite.

Tools Git, sh (zsh, bash), Docker.

Intermediate

Languages C, C#, Scala, Kotlin, Haskell. Databases ElasticSearch, ClickHouse.

Other AWS, Terraform.

Open source projects

- renamer *Rust* github.com/adriangoransson/renamer Command line tool to batch rename files. A port of the classic perl utility rename.pl.
- Nation i Lund *Go* nationilund.se Clean, fast and easy listing of student nation events in Lund. Works by scraping the official studentlund website. Would later inspire the launch of Bitiq.
- **Pomodoro tracker** *Javascript/Vue* pomodoro-tracker.netlify.com Simple but customisable Pomodoro (study technique) "egg clock". Works just as well on mobile and desktop. Available offline with service workers and has notification support.

References available upon request